Krista Loven

Full stack software engineer and enthusiastic problem solver. JavaScript and Ruby focused, with an aptitude for learning new technologies. Demonstrated ability to drive project results with limited time and resources, honed through previous experience in the nonprofit sector.

CONTACT

- Seattle, WA
- (218) 831-4396
- krista.loven.87@gmail.com
- http://www.kristaloven.me
- **Github**
- <u>LinkedIn</u>

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, JSX, React Native, Expo, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, AWS, S3, Github, Heroku, Postgres, SQLite, Bootstrap, Material UI, Semantic UI, Native Base, HTML, CSS

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Spanish, Excel, Drupal, iMovie, MailChimp, CRM Databases

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

SEATTLE 2019

Certificate in Full Stack Software Development

New York University

NEW YORK CITY 2016, 3.8 GPA

Bachelor of Arts in Spanish and Politics, Human Rights, & Development

Minor in Social Entrepreneurship

INTERESTS

Board games, card games, puzzles, kayaking, horse riding, volunteering

PROJECTS

Telephone — Entertaining party game application which applies drawing to the childhood classic

JavaScript | React Native | Expo | Native Base | Ruby on Rails | S3 <u>FRONTEND</u> — <u>BACKEND</u> — <u>DEMO</u>

- React Native IOS mobile application streamlined with Redux
- Integrated with Facebook user authentication
- S3 image storage allows users to view past games on any device
- Easy to use touch drawing implemented with Expo-Pixi

Chat — Socket-based group chat application JavaScript | React | Bootstrap | Ruby on Rails | ActionCable FRONTEND — BACKEND — DEMO

- Live chat allows users to communicate through topic based channels, as well as create new channels
- React user interface enhanced by Bootstrap styling for seamless user experience

Crazy Eights — *CLI implementation of the classic card game*Ruby | Active Record | SQLite | Deck Of Cards API | Colorize
GITHUB — DEMO

- Ruby CLI application integrated with the Deck Of Cards API
- Developed with an Al computer opponent for users to play against

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

American Corporate Partners — Manager & Team Lead, Women's Veteran Mentorship Program

NEW YORK, NY — AUGUST 2016 - JULY 2019

- Redesigned webpage, MailChimp marketing and YouTube presence.
- Led programs strategy for a community of 450+ active professional development mentorships and 2000+ alum.
- Increase program participation by 120%, events by 150%, and event attendance by 500% from 2017 to 2018.

Brooklyn Bridge Park Conservancy — *Program Associate*

BROOKLYN, NY — JUNE 2015 - AUGUST 2016

- Managed scheduling, planning and production of over 50 low cost and free public events held on the Community Dock.
- Directed the Youth Kayak Program and provided on the water instruction for up to 15 youth at a time.